<Document>
# Chemistry

Chemistry is a subsection of the Medical department but also the science of combining reagents together to make a product. What you know of real-life chemistry and pharmacology may be thrown to the wind; this is nothing like it.

## Basic tools
Your most basic tool for chemistry will be your trusty beaker. These most commonly come in 2 sizes, normal and large. They hold 50u and 100u of reagents, respectively.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LargeBeaker"/>
</Box>
These hold all your reagents, be it a raw material like [color=#434b4d]iron[/color], a medicine like [color=#ffaa00]bicaridine[/color], or a weapon like [color=#fa00af]napalm[/color]. Careful not to drop them, as they are made out of glass and can shatter easily when thrown or dropped. Anything inside the beaker will be spilled on the floor if the beaker breaks, so if you're working with a potentially dangerous chemical like [color=#a1000b]polytrinic acid[/color], keep an eye on glimmer!

There are more containers out there for you to find. Don't be afraid to ask for help!

## Commonly Used Machines
The chemical dispenser is what all of chemistry revolves around. However, don't go looking for one expecting a list of every chemical, because you will be disappointed. The chem dispenser can synthesize most of the raw reagents in the game, which is plenty for normal medicinal use and enough for normal offensive use.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemDispenser"/>
</Box>
The reagent grinder is a multipurpose device used in multiple areas of work, be it hydroponics, cooking, or in this case, chemistry. Within the context of chemistry, you will most commonly use this device to grind [color=#7e009e]plasma[/color], or to grind up mysterious pills to see what's inside. To use the machine, first simply insert a sufficently sized container, and then the object(s) you would like to grind or juice.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenReagentGrinder"/>
</Box>
The ChemMaster 4000 is not a required machine if you're only looking to drink or inject medicines, however if you find yourself in a position where you need to make pills/bottles of medicine (or perhaps a poison like [color=#a1000b]bleach[/color]), this is the machine for the job. To use the machine, simply insert a sufficently sized container full of the reagent you'd like to turn into a pill/bottle. Next, fill the buffer of the machine with the aforementioned reagent from the container, and repeat until you have a satisfactory amount of reagents inside the buffer. Don't worry about accidental mixing of reagents inside the buffer, as they do not react when inside the buffer. The buffer can also hold an unlimited amount of reagents, so fill it with a vast library of chemicals if you so desire. Once you have enough reagents in the buffer, insert a pill canister or bottle into the machine, adjust the dosage and amount of pills/units of reagent to your desire, and click the "dispense" button. A bottle/pill container with the requested items will appear in your active hand.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="chem_master"/>
</Box>
## Basic medicinal chemical mixes to know
- [color=#731024]Inaprovaline[/color], an emergency airloss cure, is made with 1u [color=#808080]oxygen[/color], 1u [color=#3e464a]carbon[/color], and 1u [color=#ffffff]sugar[/color]
- [color=#ffaa00]Bicardine[/color], which heals 4 brute damage per unit, is made with 1u [color=#731024]inaprovaline[/color], and 1u [color=#3e464a]carbon[/color].
- [color=#bf3d19]Kelotane[/color], a light burn medication (heals 2u of burn/unit) with no overdose limit, is made with 1u [color=#364266]silicon[/color], and 1u [color=#3e464a]carbon[/color].
- [color=#0041a8]Dexalin[/color], a weak airloss and bloodloss medication, and the precursor to [color=#4da0bd]Dexalin+[/color], is made with 5u [color=#7e009e]plasma[/color], and 2u [color=#808080]oxygen[/color]. The plasma is not consumed in the reaction. It should be said that this medicine nor [color=#4da0bd]Dexalin+[/color] stops your bloodloss, they only heal the damage from it.
- [color=#4da0bd]Dexalin+[/color], a hugely helpful airloss and bloodloss medication (heals 7u asphyxiation and 6u bloodloss/unit), is made with 1u [color=#434b4d]iron[/color], 1u [color=#0041a8]Dexalin[/color], and 1u [color=#3e464a]carbon[/color].
- [color=#47289e]Dylovene[/color], a general anti-toxin (heals 2 poison/unit), is made with 1u [color=#c6c8cc]potassium[/color], 1u [color=#364266]silicon[/color],and 1u [color=#808080]nitrogen[/color]

There's way more medicinal chemicals out there, some better than those listed! And on top of that, there's offensive chemicals to learn, too. Not to mention chemicals used in bartending. Don't be afraid to ask someone if a chemical that does a particular job exists. Usually it does! You can find all existing chemicals, their recipes, and effects listed on the wiki at https://wiki.nyanotrasen.moe/Chemistry.
</Document>
