<Document>
# Shogi

Shogi is the board game of Japanese chess.

## Controls

The board game Shogi has a couple controls in addition to the ones all usual board games have.
Of course, there is the standard [color=#a4885c][keybind="Use"/][/color] to pick up and move pieces,
but in Shogi, pieces can be promoted with [color=#a4885c][keybind="UseSecondary"/][/color],
and when captured, a piece can be rotated with [color=#a4885c][keybind="ActivateItemInWorld"/][/color] to change sides.

## Gameplay

Shogi is a complex game, and the depth of its strategies can only be briefly touched upon here.
There are vastly superior resources out there to teach you how to play, but this will get you started.

## Pieces

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiKing" Caption="King"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiKingJeweled" Caption="Jeweled King" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The king functions much the same as in chess. When put into checkmate, the game is over.
Black, known as sente, plays the Jeweled King (or jeweled general) and goes first.
White, known as gote, plays the King (or king general) and goes second.

The king is able to move 1 tile in any direction that would not result in it being checked.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiBishop" Caption="Bishop" Rotation="180"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiBishopPromoted" Caption="(Promoted)" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The bishop moves similarly to the bishop in chess.
When promoted, it gains the ability to move 1 tile in all directions.
It is usually referred to as a horse when promoted, based on the Chinese character the promoted version has.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiGold" Caption="Gold General" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The gold general is able to move 1 tile in any direction other than diagonally backwards.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiKnight" Caption="Knight" Rotation="180"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiKnightPromoted" Caption="(Promoted)" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The knight moves similarly as in chess, in an L shaped pattern: two tiles forward and one tile to the side.
The key difference for a shogi knight is that this knight cannot move backwards.

When promoted, the knight moves like a gold general.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiLance" Caption="Lance" Rotation="180"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiLancePromoted" Caption="(Promoted)" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The lance moves straight ahead for as many tiles as the owner wants. When promoted, the lance moves like a gold general.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiPawn" Caption="Pawn" Rotation="180"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiPawnPromoted" Caption="(Promoted)" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The pawn moves like a pawn in chess, one tile forward at a time. Unlike chess, the shogi pawn does not have the ability to move two tiles if it has not moved yet.
When promoted, the pawn moves like a gold general.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiRook" Caption="Rook" Rotation="180"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiRookPromoted" Caption="(Promoted)" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The rook moves just like in chess, any number of tiles in any straight horizontal or vertical direction.
When promoted, it gains the ability to move 1 tile in all directions.
It is usually referred to as a dragon when promoted, based on the Chinese character the promoted version has.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiSilver" Caption="Silver General" Rotation="180"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShogiSilverPromoted" Caption="(Promoted)" Rotation="180"/>
</Box>

The silver general is able to move 1 tile in any direction other than horizontal or backwards.

When promoted, the silver general moves like a gold general.

## Capture & Drops

The most striking difference between chess and shogi is that, in shogi, when you capture your opponent's piece,
you get to keep it to play later.
When you have captured pieces, you may spend your turn to drop one into play.

There are restrictions on piece drop, such as forbidding the dropping of pieces that would have no possible moves (a pawn at the opposite edge of the board, for example),
or dropping an unpromoted pawn on the same file as another,
or dropping a pawn to complete a mate.

</Document>
