<Document>
# Charges & Sentencing

This section lists all [color=#a4885c]criminal charges[/color], their [color=#a4885c]sentences[/color] as well as how to sentence a crime.

## Sentencing a Crime
- Find the charge with the highest minimum sentence and consider it a [color=#a4885c]Primary Charge[/color]. Add brig time between its minimum and maximum.
- For each other charge, [color=#a4885c]compound[/color] them by adding brig time in accordance with its limit as below.
- In both steps, make sure to consider the severity of the crime as it may wildly vary based on damage done, area tresspassed etc.
- You may further adjust the sentence based on extenuaning or aggravating circumstances.
- If the brig time for one sentence is higher than 20 minutes, you are authorized to [color=#a4885c]permabrig[/color] the convict.
- Any non-brig punishment is applied at discretion of one passing the sentence. The exception is any [color=#a4885c]Capital Crime[/color], which means a mandatory demotion to Assistant and [color=#a4885c]Abuse of Power[/color] and [color=#a4885c]Conduct Unbecoming[/color], which means a mandatory demotion.

Remember that [color=#a4885c]Solicitation[/color], [color=#a4885c]Accesory[/color], [color=#a4885c]Attempt[/color] or [color=#a4885c]Conspiracy[/color] to a crime is equivalent to having actually commited that crime.

The charges will list name, Primary Sentence and Compound Limit. A brig time of 0 should result in [color=#a4885c]Catch & Release[/color].

## Misdemeanours

[color=#a4885c]Hooliganism[/color] | Brig until compliant | Brig until compliant
- To intentionally engage in disruptive conduct.

[color=#a4885c]Trespassing[/color] | 0-7 min | 3 min
- To enter an area and refuse to leave where one is unauthorized and uninvited.

[color=#a4885c]Evading arrest[/color] | 0-3 min | 1 min
- To non-violently escape or avoid arrest.

[color=#a4885c]Contempt of Court[/color] | 5 min | 5 min
- To conduct oneself disruptively and disrespectfully before the court.

[color=#a4885c]Insubordination[/color] | 0-3 min | 2 min + Demotion
- To disobey a lawful direct order from one’s superior officer.

[color=#a4885c]Misdemeanor Possession[/color] | 0-3 min | 1.5 min
- To possess items one is not authorized to have.

[color=#a4885c]Vandalism[/color] | 0-3 min | 1.5 min
- To intentionally deface or superficially damage property.

[color=#a4885c]Endangerment[/color] | 3-6 min | 2 min
- To recklessly put yourself or others in danger through your malpractice, action or inaction.

[color=#a4885c]Animal Cruelty[/color] | 3-6 min | 2 min
- To inflict unnecessary suffering on a non-sapient being with malicious intent.

[color=#a4885c]Theft[/color] | 0-4 min | 2 min
- To take property without consent, depriving authorized users of its intended use.

[color=#a4885c]Assault[/color] | 0-3 min | 1.5 min
- To threaten to use physical force against someone while also having the capability and/or intent to carry out that threat.

## Felonies

[color=#a4885c]Battery[/color] | 0-5 min | 2.5 min
- To effect unsolicited or unlawful physical contact with a person or to thusly administer a substance upon them, directly or indirectly.

[color=#a4885c]Resisting Arrest[/color] | 3-6 min | 2 min
- To intentionally and violently resist arrest or confinement.

[color=#a4885c]Rioting[/color] | 0-5 min | 2 min
- To engage in a public disturbance which involves damage to property.

[color=#a4885c]Conduct Unbecoming[/color] | 0-6 min | 3 min
- To willfully abandon an obligation that is critical to the station’s continued operation, or to disrepute Nyanotrasen by grossly improper conduct.

[color=#a4885c]Abuse of Power[/color] | 3-6 min & Demotion | 2.5 min
- To grossly oppress an individual as someone with authority over that individual.

[color=#a4885c]Black Marketeering[/color] | 6-12 min | 3 min
- To sell or distribute restricted items or substances.

[color=#a4885c]Obstruction of Justice[/color] | 6-12 min | 3 min
- To willfully disobey a decree of the court or a warrant or prevent one from service.

[color=#a4885c]Felony Possession[/color] | 5-10 min | 2 min
- To be in unauthorized possession of highly restricted items or items of particular danger.

[color=#a4885c]Sabotage[/color] | 3-6 min | 2.5 min
- To engage in malicious actions that hinder the integrity of the station and/or the function of the crew.

[color=#a4885c]Malicious Psionic Activity[/color] | 3-6 min | 2 min + Mindbreak
- To use psychic abilities to commit crime.

[color=#a4885c]Maiming[/color] | 4-8 min | 2.5 min
- To inflict physical injury with the intent to disfigure or impair function.

[color=#a4885c]Unauthorized Decorporealization[/color] | 5-10 min | 2 min + Decorporealization
- To unlawfully strip a being’s mind from their own body.

[color=#a4885c]Unauthorized Mindbreaking[/color] | 4-8 min | 2 min + Demotion and/or Mindbreak
- To unlawfully rid a psychic of their powers.

[color=#a4885c]Manslaughter[/color] | 6-12 min | 5 min
- To effect violence upon a person, resulting in their death.

## Capital Crime

[color=#a4885c]Sexual Harassment[/color] | Permabrig or Capital Punishment
- To harass someone or attempt to force or coerce them into sexual relations.
- [color=#a00000]May result in PERMANENT game ban.[/color]

[color=#a4885c]Sedition[/color] | Demotion to Assistant + 12 min-permabrig or Capital Punishment
- To act to overthrow or subvert the established Chain of Command without lawful and legitimate cause.

[color=#a4885c]Espionage[/color] | Demotion to Assistant + 12 min-permabrig or Capital Punishment
- To be an unauthorized holder of classified information and/or technology, provide it to an unauthorized recipient, or to intentionally misrepresent oneself as being an official of Nyanotrasen.

[color=#a4885c]Kidnapping[/color] | Demotion to Assistant + 12 min-permabrig or Capital Punishment
- To unlawfully remove or confine an individual against their will.

[color=#a4885c]Terrorism[/color] | Demotion to Assistant + 12 min-permabrig or Capital Punishment
- To engage in maliciously destructive actions which make uninhabitable or inoperable a vessel or its part.

[color=#a4885c]Murder[/color] | Permabrig or Capital Punishment
- To kill a sapient being with malicious intent and premeditation.

</Document>
